[in English] The resolution to deny
ABS-CBN's franchise application
is hereby adopted.
Pursuant to Section 49 of the Rules
of the House of Representatives
all House Bills and House Resolutions
relative to the grant or renewal
of the franchise application
of ABS-CBN Corporation
are hereby laid on the table.
[congressman] The committee secretary
is hereby directed
to inform all the authors
of the bills and resolutions...
[in Filipino]
Why are you still watching that?
The jobs we get for our talents
are from ABS-CBN.
Where else would we
find work for them?
This is a huge problem.
[Matthew in English]
Well, strangely enough
that's the least of our problems.
Maybe we can look at it
as an opportunity.
[in Filipino] Just think about it.
How many decades
have the studios and networks
been running the industry?
That's why we're thinking
there's no more work for our talents.
Okay, that's valid,
but where's the opportunity there?
[in English] Maybe it's time
to rethink how the industry works.
[Gab in Filipino] Let's explore
new platforms for our talents.
[in English] Maybe ABS-CBN's closure
is a signal for us to make
some changes or adjustments.
[in Filipino] Right?
It does sound like an opportunity.
But what's the point
if SAM shuts down?
[in English] Guys, I'm sorry.
It's not your fault.
[in Filipino] Yeah, come on.
[in English]
It's not your fault, Matt.
It's your younger self's fault.
[in Filipino]
If you didn't cheat on Gina
then we'd have money to pay for SAM.
- You're such a flirt.
- [chuckles]
Gee, thanks.
It was a joke!
But if SAM does close
I don't think I'll move agencies.
Me neither.
What, do I go to Galaxy? Eww.
- I know, right?
- I'll just write a screenplay.
I can follow Joey to Canada.
Be an IT guy there.
You know IT?
I didn't know how
to manage talents before either.
- But you'll stay busy, businessman.
- Right.
[in English] No, but the thing is...
I don't want to do anything else.
And I don't want to be anywhere else.
[in Filipino]
We want to buy SAM because
we want to keep
Samuel's legacy alive.
Yeah.
[in English]
That name is magic in this business.
[in Filipino]
The bank hasn't said no yet.
[in English] There's still a chance.
We still have three days.
[in Filipino]
But one thing we have to realize
whether or not we get that loan
things will never be the same.
[somber music]
[Helen in English]
Well, look who's here.
[in Filipino] How are you?
[in English] Not that I care.
[in Filipino]
That's just my standard greeting.
But I'm a decent woman,
so I'll ask you to sit.
[Aleta] Helen.
We're too old to be pulling
each other's hair, aren't we?
[scoffs]
Well...
Don't you have questions for me?
About me and Samuel?
Nothing.
I no longer care about that.
[in English] It's all in the past.
Exactly.
[in Filipino]
You can't be serious, Aleta.
[in English] You know I would not
take your money for anything.
And I would not do anything
to make you feel better.
[in Filipino]
That document may have my signature
but it's also for Matthew
Andrea, and Gabriel too.
[in English] Like I said,
I would not do anything
to make you feel better.
Then do it for Samuel.
Do it in his memory.
All the memories I have with Samuel
include you.
[in Filipino]
Why would I want to relive that?
It was Samuel who chose to leave me.
[in English] I don't believe you.
He would've left me for you
the minute he had a chance.
[in Filipino] And he had his chances.
But he didn't leave you.
It's because he loved you,
that's why he stayed.
But above you and me
he loved SAM more.
Compared to that...
neither of us could win.
[in English]
I can give you my answer right now.
No.
[in Filipino]
When you realize the truth...
[in English]
I told you I would not do anything
to make you feel better.
[thrilling music]
[overlapping dialogue]
[overlapping dialogue continues]
[staff 1] Move fast.
We have a lot of stuff to move.
[staff 2] Careful. This might fall.
[staff 3] Hey, wait!
[indistinct chatter]
Come on!
Why is this so heavy?
Um, guys.
This situation is temporary.
The old office badly needs
extensive renovation.
[Matthew in English] Every little bit
that we can save will go a long way.
That's why we all have
to share this space.
[in Filipino]
Gab and I stay down here?
Am I back to being a junior manager?
Are we redesigning interiors now?
[frustrated sigh]
Is there coffee in this dump?
Coming, ma'am!
Camille!
[Andrea] Tell Deo
to move our tables up there.
- Now.
- [Camille] Okay, ma'am.
[Matthew] Still no word
from the bank.
Unfortunately, we were not able
to raise the money on our own.
But SAM has a good reputation.
Let's hope
the bank sees that.
So this means we keep on working?
What do we do while waiting?
If we get new management,
will you stay?
To answer everyone's question...
What do we do?
The truth is, we don't know.
Guys...
[coffee machine whirring loudly]
God, forget the coffee.
I said, forget the coffee!
I'm sorry!
Goodness, I can't.
If SAM must go down
and the Screen Spirit Awards
is truly our last, our biggest event
then we must go out with a bang!
- Right?
- [Camille] With a bang!
Yes, with a bang!
Wow, how beautiful!
You'll be a head-turner, babe!
[Noemi] We all have to look good.
They can't know our struggles.
Win or lose,
whether SAM closes or not
we will be our grandest.
Slickest!
[employee 1] The freshest.
Most debonair.
Instagram-ready.
Best dressed!
I spent the best years
of my life in Shine.
We are Shine!
- [Matthew] We are Shine!
- [Camille] We are Shine!
We are Shine!
- We are Shine!
- [Camille] Bang!
I'll go first!
Okay, fine.
- Miss Andrea!
- I'll go next, okay?
- Okay, Sir Matthew.
- Miss Andrea!
- Yeah?
- Phone for you.
- At your office.
- I'll be back.
Andrea here.
Hey, get these flowers off my desk.
[employee 2] Huh?
- These flowers! Are you deaf?
- [employee 2] Right away, ma'am!
[Rina over phone speaker] I miss you.
I miss your smile.
I miss your smell.
I feel so alone, Andrea.
I wish you were here.
Can we talk?
Hello, Rina, yeah.
What?
[Chin] Hey, let's go there!
[Camille] Noemi, let's go.
[Andrea] Hello, yeah, Rina, um...
Hi...
[sobs, sniffles]
[exhales sharply]
[Matthew] What happened?
[whimpers]
Rina just called.
I already have a lot on my mind...
[quivers]
...and now she jumps in
and complicates everything.
[sobs]
We lost Samuel.
We're losing our talents.
We're about to lose SAM.
And with my mom's situation...
And we're all working
in this cramped office.
I don't even know where to start...
to fix everything,
and then she calls.
So you miss Rina?
No! [sniffles]
You don't miss Rina?
Yes...
No!
I don't...
I don't know.
[Zsa Zsa] ...the whale sharks.
Are you ready?
Let's go!
[lively music]
We're so busy with work
that we don't have time
for boyfriends.
Is it yummy?
Yes!
[lively music continues]
[Brandon cheering]
We have a lot on our plate,
literally!
I hope you enjoyed watching!
Please subscribe, okay?
This is really high!
I'm going to jump!
Here we go! [chuckles]
[squeals]
- Success!
- I told you so!
I feel like crying.
This is excellent! Great job!
Uh...
But what's it for?
Um...
This is a preview
of what's in store for our talents.
Yes, we're working
on the social media presence
- of our talents.
- True!
You always say, Sir Gab
"This is the future
of entertainment!"
Now our content
can be seen everywhere
so the SAM community is growing!
That's right,
and with this kind of slate...
Believe me, we're projecting
around a hundred thousand
- up to millions of followers!
- [Sofie] Millions!
- Millions!
- Yes! There's more! Gosh.
We're seeing dozens of offers
from lots of brands
for all our talents!
That's on top of TV and other media!
Take note!
[in English] So who thought of this?
[in Filipino]
Chin started it with Rob and Kiray.
[Gab] Good job, Chin.
[Camille] Then we built on it
with Noemi's vision.
[Matthew] But, you know
some of these talents
might not be here anymore...
- Then we'll find more!
- There's a lot, Sit Matthew.
- And we'll make more content!
- Yes.
- We can do this!
- Yes!
Correct!
[sighs]
Wonderful job, guys!
- [squeals]
- Good work, good work.
- This is going to be viral.
- My gosh.
- [Daisy] Your nails are pretty!
- [Sofie] Right?
- [Daisy] Like candles.
- [Deo] Uh...
Ms. Sofie.
Can you type and print this for me?
Ah!
Sure thing.
This is a quick-dry polish, anyway.
Leave it here.
Hm...
Hey.
Are you serious? Why?
[exhales sharply]
I can't do this anymore.
- [Sofie] What?
- He's being an idiot.
You shouldn't have fixed things
if you're going to leave anyway.
- I can't do this anymore.
- [Sofie] I know.
If we can't stop you, go to Admin
and get me an envelope for this
so once I print it,
I'll hand it in there.
You're not going to cry?
We're good.
What are your plans?
Why are you leaving?
[Daisy] What will you do
when you leave SAM?
No idea. What are you guys doing?
I'm already doing it.
And Sofie is going to be an actress.
[Sofie] Right.
I have so many side hustles
here at SAM.
I'm sure I'll live.
Plus there are loans I've given out.
- Wait, you still owe me.
- Envelope.
What's up with him?
What's he up to?
Not in here.
- No, sir.
- Is this SAM?
Not here either.
- Not here either?
- Yes, sir.
We've been looking all over.
- Hey, Deo!
- Sir Monsour!
We've been looking for you guys!
We're over here, sir.
- Is Andrea there?
- Yes, sir, she's inside.
We couldn't find her.
- I'll take you to her.
- Come on.
- Hello.
- [Gab] Mon, good to see you!
[Monsour] Hi, Gab, how are you?
- Hi, everybody.
- [employee 1] Sir Mon.
[Monsour] Hello.
Where's Andrea?
Andrea?
- [Andrea] Mon?
- Andrea?
Mon!
- Hey, I'm here!
- [Monsour] Oh!
- [Andrea] Hi! Yeah.
- [Monsour] Andrea, hi.
- Sorry about the mess.
- I didn't see you there.
Sorry.
We're just trying something new here.
So what can I do for you?
I just wanted to let you know...
- Because...
- What?
[coffee machine whirring loudly]
I want you to hear it from me.
- [muffled dialogue]
- [whirring continues]
Wait.
Hey.
Stop it, for crying out loud!
Get coconut juice!
No coffee from now on, okay!
Okay, sorry.
Again, please.
I came here to tell you personally
to let you know
that Director Lav Diaz and I
have decided
to shelve the film.
[Monsour]
We're not going to finish it.
[Andrea] But...
But you've already spent
eight million on it, right?
Uh... That's true.
- Yeah, I'm just so busy...
- Sorry I missed your call...
- I'm so unbelievably busy, yes!
- Really busy, sorry.
So for now
I really want a time out
from all this.
Well... Yeah, I understand.
Um, well, you still have
contracts with us, but...
but that can be discussed.
Why?
I'm not leaving SAM.
- You're not?
- [Monsour] No!
Come on.
I've decided that I want to run.
Where are you going?
[chuckles]
No, I want to run for mayor.
- [Andrea] Oh, politics. Okay.
- [Monsour] Yes.
I really want to serve my countrymen.
If I can't be a hero
in the movies anymore
maybe I can be a hero in real life.
- [Andrea] Of course.
- [Monsour] Right?
It's a new adventure,
and I can do it.
Of course, you can. We can do this!
- [cell phone vibrates]
- My question is
can Shine help me with this?
Uh...
Do you have a running mate in mind?
Hm?
Running mate?
[Andrea] To make things easier,
you should each create a story.
When you're done, pass it on to me.
So it's easier for me
to narrow down what we'll do.
And then, for the options,
start from the top.
- I'll know what to include.
- Excuse me...
Yes?
Can I talk to Camille for a second?
Sure, we're all done.
For me?
It's beautiful!
Can I pull this off?
Of course you can!
- Yes, you can.
- You like it?
Thank you.
Let me ask you.
Do you like?
- Looks good!
- No...
[chuckles]
I mean, do you like it?
- [Camille] Thank you!
- Aww...
[Sofie] Oh, my god, Rob! You're here!
Everyone, Rob!
Our Best Actor nominee!
[all cheering]
Thank you so much!
This is my mom.
My beautiful mother.
Sir Gab, I brought my mom.
- Congrats.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you!
- Hi!
Chin!
- How are you?
- I'm fine.
- How about you? I'm proud of you!
- Well, you know...
[cell phone ringing]
Oh, shoot.
Matt.
Good morning, Mr. Villacin.
How can I help you?
[over speaker phone] It's Frank.
Following up on our new partnership.
Partnership?
[Frank] Whatever you want to call it.
I don't care for labels.
What I want is that you work with me.
One, I can guarantee your bank loan.
Two, you get a permanent client
in yours truly.
Uh... Frank?
We're not interested in that kind
of business relationship.
You have no other options.
We all know that SAM
is in dire straits right now.
Allow me to help you.
Um...
How?
Join me and my team
and I will be your biggest asset.
My name is gold
in the banking community.
You'll get your loan
and your problems will disappear.
It's that simple.
Oh!
Thank you.
But we'll have to tell this
to Gab first, okay?
Yeah. It's okay.
But don't make me wait too long.
I've waited long enough
and I don't like that.
Oh!
No worries.
It will just take a few minutes.
I'll call you back, okay?
[cell phone beeps]
Hey, Gab?
Chin!
[grunts] Thank you!
You're welcome, of course. Always.
For everything.
But...
are you really okay?
Yes, I am.
I'm really okay.
Proud of you.
Um, Rob?
- [Rob] Yes?
- Can you...
Can you come here, please?
Go.
[clears throat]
[Frank over phone] Hello, SAM.
What's wrong with your head, Andrea?
[chuckles] Mr. Villacin,
it's been that way since you called.
Uh...
Mr. Villacin, hello. This is Gabriel.
[Frank in Filipino]
I told you, call me Frank.
Uh...
We would've wanted
to talk to you in person
but we're kind of busy at the moment.
So this will do.
[Frank] You're busy?
Busy closing shop?
Just kidding.
I know you guys
are still the best in the business
so I'll stay with you
as long as you need me.
About that...
We talked about your proposal.
And we've decided
that the best way
to go about it is to...
not go about it.
We respectfully decline.
No, let me rephrase that.
- [Gab] We are rejecting your offer.
- [frustrated exhale]
[grunts]
What did you say?
Okay.
Now you listen to me.
You need me!
You're making a big mistake!
Someone important to me once said
that I should listen to my heart
and listen to my gut feel.
And you know what? Right now...
our gut tells us
we have everything
we need right here.
Frank.
[in English] Are you sure?
I will never make this offer again.
We're actually quite sure,
Mr. Villacin.
Thank you.
Okay.
Rob, I'm so sorry.
I just wanted you to hear the call.
[in Filipino] It's okay.
I know you wouldn't do that to me.
And, Ms. Andrea?
That's me.
I'm the one who's staying.
[in English] I will stay for as long
as you want me.
Thank you.
- Oh, Chin?
- [Chin] Mm-hm?
- It's time for Rob's makeup.
- Okay. Let's go.
Oh!
I almost forgot.
What's this?
[suspenseful music]
Think of it as an eraser.
You can watch it tomorrow.
[sighs]
Yuni!
Call Helen Mendiola. Now!
The entertainment industry
is so powerful.
People watch our every move.
They worship our artists and talents.
We can control what they wear
where they go on holiday
even how they think.
But people in this industry
don't realize
that power comes with responsibility.
Just think about it.
Imagine what we can do
if we use that power for good
instead of just wasting it.
- [clears throat]
- Thanks.
So, any news?
A lot.
The bank rejected our application.
They won't give us the loan.
[sighs]
Darn that Frank Villacin.
[in English] You know...
I'm not sure it's Frank.
[in Filipino] He's right.
It's a risky business.
When you consider the state we're in
who would risk giving us a loan?
Anyway, uh...
it's too late now.
So I guess that's it.
She's not saying who it is.
But she'll be making
an announcement soon.
I bet it's Paul Amir.
What do we do now?
[groans]
[somber music]
[indistinct chatter]
[inaudible dialogue]
- Sir Gab!
- Yo, Sir Gab!
Thank you!
Pa!
[Camille] Thank you!
Ms. Andrea, thank you!
Thank you!
For Ms. Andrea?
Ms. Andrea!
Someone sent this.
- [chuckles]
- Oh! Thank you.
It's from Rina.
- Ah!
- Oh!
She says I should use it later.
Don't forget! Joey will call later!
Okay, thanks! I'll take care of it.
[in English] Did we fail?
- [laughter]
- [indistinct chatter]
Matty?
I don't think we failed.
Really?
I don't think so.
[Andrea] You know what?
[in Filipino] I think
let's not tell them anything yet.
[in English] Well, I'm happy.
♪ ... all alone ♪
[in Filipino]
But I'd be happier if we owned SAM.
[chuckles]
♪ ... all alone ♪
[in English]
You did your best, Matty.
We all did.
Yeah.
♪ I don't feel all right being one ♪
♪ All alone from beginning to end ♪
[Camille] Picture!
Let's take pictures!
♪ Oh, can anyone lend me a friend? ♪
♪ To help me around the bend ♪
[employee 1] Three, two, one!
[camera shutter clicks]
♪ A friend to the very end ♪
♪ 'Cause I don't feel all right
Being one ♪
Hey, let's go!
♪ No, I don't feel all right
Being one ♪
♪ I'll be a friend to you ♪
Pa, wait,
let's take a picture together.
♪ It's great fun when we're two ♪
♪ Not just you all alone ♪
Where's Gab?
Oh, no!
Gab? Let's go!
♪ How about singing a little tune? ♪
♪ Blending in harmony too ♪
♪ Singing like we were made
For each other, together ♪
♪ It's like we do it all the time ♪
Oops!
- Wow, what was that?
- [giggles]
Sorry, we're still here.
Really sorry.
We thought you were all gone.
- [Daisy] Goodness.
- Sir Gab.
- We didn't see a thing!
- You dropped this.
- Thank you!
- [Daisy] Nothing!
- I have vertigo.
- [chuckles]
This is your fault.
[thrilling music]
[crowd cheering]
[indistinct chatter]
Here they come!
The big stars are starting to arrive!
[vlogger] We'll soon find out
who'll be lauded
as the best of the year.
[camera shutters clicking]
[thrilling music continues]
My dates tonight.
Because I'm relevant.
[laughs]
#SSAMAZING
You're here early. What a shock.
Did you sleep here?
And why were you late?
Struggled fitting in your girdle?
You are both nominated
for Best Actress
how do you feel about that?
I wish my dear friend here good luck.
[in English]
May the best actress win.
[reporters cheer, laugh]
I want to introduce you all
to our newest artist, Sofie Lasola.
- You're really a celebrity now!
- [Sofie] Oh, my god!
- I'm proud of you!
- [Andrea] Sofie, you're so pretty.
Thank you so much, Ms. Andrea!
I didn't expect so many people.
It'll be a while before this starts.
- Go socialize.
- [Andrea] Yeah, go and have fun!
- Go!
- Let's go see the band.
- Coming through.
- Chin, let's go.
[Noemi] Chin, let's go!
[lively music]
Hi, guys!
One gin and tonic, please.
Excuse me.
Wait for your turn.
Hey, where's my gin and tonic?
I've been waiting...
Can't you just...
Gin and tonic, no ice,
with a slice of lemon.
[giggles]
I really want this to work.
I do too.
Let's make it work.
♪ Don't ♪
♪ Don't be startled ♪
[keyboard clacking]
I talked to one of your talents.
They're so happy with your work!
- And the way you use social media...
- Yeah
...Shine is doing work!
Remember, I told you before
that there's a project out there
that's totally fit for you.
I know you guys are really not afraid
to take on challenges.
You think this will work?
Of course it will work!
Call us. You're welcome
to join us anytime.
Well, my plan is to run for mayor.
If I'm lucky, that is.
Who would you like to team up with?
- Bojack!
- [Monsour] He's here!
[reporter] I'm so shocked!
Boom!
- You all know Niño Muhlach, right?
- Of course, yes!
[Monsour] This is our new tandem.
Mon and Niño.
MonNiño!
VOTE! BRAVE, DEPENDABLE,
AND NO-NONSENSE!
Thank you!
- [reporter] Mother Aleta, over here.
- Over here?
Mother Aleta, look over here, please.
Okay.
Mother Aleta!
Mother!
If you'll excuse us. Thanks.
Thank you, Matthew. Thank you.
SAM has been sold.
I just don't know yet who bought it.
5What now?
For all we know, as early as Monday
we'll have a new boss.
What would you like to drink?
Nothing. I want to go inside.
But it hasn't started yet.
No, but it will.
No need to accompany me.
You can sit with us at SAM's table.
No, thanks.
That's too far from the stage.
I'll see you.
[upbeat music]
It's the first time we're attending
an event like this without Samuel.
I know. I wonder
what he'll say if he can see us.
He'll scold us for sure.
No doubt.
But for me, one thing's for sure.
I'm very proud of this team.
Oh, yeah. Definitely.
And I'm sure Samuel is too.
We're SAM. We'll be all right.
- Hi, sir!
- Hi, Christian! How are you?
[announcer] Good evening!
[Matthew] Joel!
Welcome to this year's
Screen Spirit Awards.
How are you?
Here are your hosts
Karylle and Robi Domingo!
[grandiose music]
[in English] Good evening, everyone!
Whoo! [chuckles]
I'm Karylle, and together
with my wonderful co-host, Robi
we are here to welcome you
to the grandest night
of Philippine entertainment.
- This is the Screen Spirit Awards!
- Screen Spirit Awards!
[Robi] Here we go!
[traditional Filipino music]
- Ms. Andrea, we'll be right back...
- Okay.
[in Filipino]
This program is insanely long.
That's because
we're not winning any awards.
[giggles]
Whatever.
I'll just go to the bathroom, okay?
- [gasps]
- [chuckles]
[in English] So, you decided
to join the sinking ship?
[in Filipino]
Well, it wasn't a difficult decision.
For sure, especially for your kind.
My kind?
Those who never use their brains
and think with their hearts instead.
You know.
Those...
stupid divas!
[door closes]
Goodness gracious.
This jerk.
Where have you been?
- I was in the bathroom.
- Oh, come on!
No regard for other people.
Oh, okay!
[in English] And our Bright Star
of the evening is...
[Robi] Ms. Maricel Soriano!
So beautiful.
You know, Bright Star is synonymous
with the Diamond Star.
- [Karylle] With a beautiful sash!
- [Robi] Yeah.
What does she get?
Here it is!
Tonight's Bright Star gets
a year's supply
of Bright Cooking Oil!
- Wow!
- [audience applauds]
- [Karylle] Give her a big hand!
- [Hector] Hey, Pops!
Hey, Hec!
[in Filipino] You're still here.
You should've joined us earlier.
It's fine, we had to pack our gear.
[Robi] Ms. Maricel Soriano!
[in English] Hec, I'm sorry.
You know what, Pops? It's okay.
Seriously, it happened
before we were born.
[in Filipino]
Camille and I are fine with it.
[Hector] And actually,
I like her a lot.
It's all good now.
And besides, you're in show business.
Those kinds of dramas are normal.
Your mom's still angry?
I'm sure you understand, Pops.
[Robi in English]
Actually, we are not yet done
because we got our last special award
for the evening
and that is our Sparkling Star
of the night
and that person is none other than...
Ms. Snooky Serna!
[crowd cheering]
[Karylle] Also looking great
in her black ensemble, with a fringe!
[in Filipino] Matching her tattoos.
Bright and Sparkle.
Here is her award.
[in English] Congratulations.
Our Sparkling Star of the night gets
a year's supply
of Sparkle Laundry Bar!
- [Robi] Wow!
- I need to approve the script.
I don't want them sneaking
an endorsement into my lines.
I don't do that.
No way. What are you waiting for?
I'm next and I need my lines!
- Amateurs!
- Sir Dick, hello, I'm Chin.
- Chin?
- From SAM.
We are presenting
this Lifetime Achievement Award
to commemorate a legendary actress
of the film industry.
She starred in her first film
during the 1920s
Serene Maiden, that gave her
the nickname "Maria Clara."
Are you sure you're not gonna come?
It's okay if you arrive late.
[Zsa Zsa over phone]
No, honey, I'm too embarrassed.
They'll ask about my drunken stream.
They've all forgotten about that.
By the time I get there
you'll be done anyway.
I can just get a copy.
We'll watch it together.
Okay, yeah.
Love you. Okay. Bye, Mama.
Ms. Encarnacion Dimamatay.
♪ Late at night ♪
♪ Looking at the stars ♪
♪ I'm thinking of you, baby ♪
♪ Wondering where you are ♪
♪ When I say good night ♪
♪ Turn out the lights ♪
♪ I still lay awake,
Dreaming of you ♪
♪ Holding me tight ♪
- ♪ Starlight, star bright
- Starlight, star bright ♪
- ♪ Wish I may...
- Wish I may, wish I might ♪
♪ Won't you make him love me too? ♪
♪ Make him want to hold me too ♪
♪ And wish upon a star ♪
♪ As I do ♪
Ladies and gentlemen
my legendary mother,
Ms. Zsa Zsa Padilla.
My daughter, Karylle.
♪ I'll never stop ♪
♪ Wishing on that star ♪
♪ I'll never stop wishing ♪
- ♪ Till my dreams come true
- Till my dreams come true ♪
- ♪ And I can hold you
- And I can hold you ♪
- ♪ And love you
- And love you ♪
- ♪ Make him want to hold me too
- Make him want to hold me too ♪
- ♪ And promise me forever
- And promise me forever ♪
- ♪ And wish upon a star
- And wish upon a star ♪
♪ I'm wishing on starlight ♪
♪ Wishing on starlight ♪
- ♪ Star bright
- Star bright ♪
- Go!
- [cheering]
[in unison]
And the 69th Screen Spirit Award
for Best Actor goes to...
[Maricel] Rod... [coughs]
...Paulate, The Lonely One.
[crowd applauding]
[Roderick] Thank you so much.
How many of these have I gotten?
I've gotten a lot.
When I heard my name called for this
I remembered when I was just 19.
I just wanted to be seen
on television, movies.
- That's it. That was my dream.
- We should go.
- But you know...
- We'll go slowly.
I was just a newbie
in the field of acting.
Yet right off the bat,
I won two awards, just like that!
I told myself,
"You are really blessed."
And when I was 22
I wanted to give the audience
what they wanted.
Hello, hello there!
Now, I've worked with these ladies.
These two right here onstage.
I've worked with them
in some of my films.
But as for the awards,
they weren't as fortunate as me.
I always end up with the awards.
But I'm not one to brag.
When I was younger...
So when I was 22 years old...
...and do anything
to entertain audiences...
...so I was 15, and even at school
I kept getting the awards.
We should go.
My legs are getting numb.
I won't take any more of your time.
When I was a child,
our house would always get flooded.
That was hard for me as a kid.
The directors would even ask me
"How do you make your...
while you're on camera,
when we're about to start
you haven't spoken a single line
teardrops roll down right on cue?"
That's how blessings work sometimes.
This is my 18th Best Actor award!
Let's hear it for me! [laughs]
Eighteen awards!
Now I'd have to remodel my house
to make space for this new award.
That's the downside
of getting awards.
The nerve of that man.
- Right?
- Define audacious.
So I would like to thank
this award-giving body.
And of course, how can I forget?
I want to thank you...
Paul Amir!
Thank you so much.
Thirty percent of my gratitude
and thirty percent
of my salary goes to you.
But not anymore.
- What was that?
- That's all.
I wasn't too prepared.
I'm sorry for my quick speech.
Thank you.
- [gasps]
- I like this.
[announcer] Let's give it up
for the national champions!
NU Pep Squad!
[upbeat music]
- Congratulations, sir.
- [Roderick] Thank you!
Roderick, excuse me.
What happened there? I mean...
You see this?
I'll let you in on a secret...
- What is it?
- Paul Amir told me that...
Now, call me a stupid diva.
- Wait a minute.
- We're done!
Or I'll knock you out.
[upbeat music]
You played me for a fool!
Hi, Paul.
I've done that to a lot of people.
[in English] Let me remind you
that I still have the documents
that you gave me.
[in Filipino]
Your talents won't be happy
when they find out
you're giving away their secrets.
Paul, if I were you
I'd burn those phony papers.
[in English] There's no truth
in any of those documents.
[in Filipino]
So it was all part of your grand plan
for me to retract my offer
to make Helen mad.
I needed to buy some time.
At my expense.
So look what happened.
We both missed out on SAM.
What, you didn't get SAM?
How could that happen
when Helen's really mad at me
for retracting my offer?
[Matthew] I didn't get it.
You didn't get it.
So who did?
[grandiose music]
[announcer] The nominees
for Best Actress are...
I think I know who bought SAM.
Who?
Lynette Marie Vicencio, Amihan and I.
Lotlot de Leon, The Sacrifice.
- Frank?
Maricel Soriano, For Alida.
Snooky Serna, Sabel's Secret.
This year's Best Actress is...
Lynette Marie Vicencio
Amihan and I.
What the heck?
This is truly shocking.
I'm so shocked. What a shocker!
Thank you!
The Best Picture award goes to
The Offering by Royal Lion Films.
To all the staff and crew
of Royal Lion
who have been working
with me for a long time
to The Offering's director
Cyrus Mariveles
and to my superb cast
headed by Ms. Lotlot De Leon
thank you so much to all of you.
I've been in this industry
for a long time.
And even though
the time may be nearing
when I won't be here anymore...
[Aleta] I believe
I have beautiful things
I could leave behind for all of you.
I introduced a lot of trends,
love teams
sexy flicks, action movies
family dramas, and more.
But in everything I've done
I've tried to keep
our showbiz world lively and vibrant.
Because I truly love this world.
Even though we've faced
more losses than wins
I'm still here. We're still here.
[crowd applauding]
So I express my gratitude
to those people
who tirelessly give their love
and care to this industry.
Even though many think
we're already obsolete.
[somber music]
Thank you all.
Thank you!
- We love you, Mother!
- [Aleta] Thank you!
[Andrea] Mother!
- We love you, Mother!
- Love you, Mother!
[Gab] Love you, Mother!
[in English]
Dick, congratulations again.
You deserve it!
[Roderick in Filipino] Thank you!
Another Best Actor award!
- [Andrea] I know!
- [Roderick] Thank you.
- Thank you.
- [Andrea] Bye!
- Many more!
- Congratulations!
Mary. Good night.
- Good night.
- I'll give you a call.
- Thank you again for coming.
- Okay.
Bye!
Bye-bye!
[sighs]
Well, what do you think?
About?
Would Maricel and Snooky take it well
if we put Roderick on SAM's roster?
That is, if we still have
a SAM roster to put him on.
Guys, did you get this?
- It's Mother Aleta.
- Mother Aleta.
Didn't you get a message?
- Go check.
- [Noemi] Why?
What?
[line ringing]
[Andrea] Noemi, let's go! Hurry up!
Mother's not picking up.
Margie texted, Mother's at home.
Home? Why didn't they bring her
to the hospital?
Right. It should be a hospital first,
then the morgue. That's protocol.
- Chin!
- What morgue?
Didn't you hear her speech?
It's like she was saying
her farewell.
As if she's about to die.
What do we do?
[Gab] Chin, shut up!
[tense music]
- Mother?
[Gab] Mother!
- [Andrea] Mother!
- [Chin] Mother!
- Mother!
- What's happening?
[Andrea] Mother! Oh, god!
- Mother?
- I was afraid this would happen.
- Mother.
- Oh, my god, Mother!
What should we do?
What... I don't know.
[glasses clinking]
Ma'am, here's your coffee.
[mumbles]
- [Gab] Mother?
- Fix me a cup.
Mother! Oh, my god!
Hm?
Mother, what happened?
You texted me saying
something happened.
SAM X MOTHER ALETA
SOMETHING HAPPENED...
Well, it was clear when I wrote that.
[giggles]
Mother, tell us what happened.
They gave me a drink backstage
because I won.
I stumbled.
And you threw up!
No, I threw up.
Why is everyone here?
I called you here just to chat.
Why would I kill myself? Lunatics.
[Gab] It's Chin's fault, Mother.
After all I've been through,
I'd commit suicide?
No.
- I don't want that.
- You're so stubborn.
Well, Mother,
maybe it's us who should be
thinking of ending things.
[Andrea] Give us some of those pills,
that'll do the job.
- [Matthew] Hey, guys. Hey.
- They're right there.
Remember that Helen sold SAM.
Most likely by Monday...
Frank Villacin will be our new boss.
Good God.
Have you told the kids?
They've told us, Mother.
That's why we raided
your wine cabinet.
These are meant for guests,
since you don't really drink, right?
Well, you already helped yourselves.
[clicks tongue] So what's the plan?
What else,
except to switch to Galaxy?
- [Camille] Yuck!
- [Sofie] Eww!
Eww, Galaxy?
Which do you prefer...
- Paul Amir?
- A big jerk.
- Frank Villacin?
- Another jerk.
[Noemi] Maybe I'll be
a domestic helper.
- [Chin] Me too.
- [Camille] I'll go home to Baguio.
Wait. In the meantime...
Let's toast to Noemi
our newest manager.
And the last! Cheers!
- [Camille] Cheers to that!
- Thank you.
[Noemi] That's harsh, Chin.
The most unfortunate one is Camille.
She's new and now she lost her job.
Yeah, just when she's getting used to
working for Andrea.
- What do you mean by that?
- [Camille] No, to be honest
I'm more afraid of Chin and Noemi now
than I am of Ms. Andrea.
Bully. Bigger bully. Biggest bully.
- What are you trying to say?
- [Chin] Just kidding.
Let's not forget to congratulate...
- Mother Aleta.
- Hm?
You deserve that award,
you really do.
Thank you, thank you!
My film only won
because they're all afraid of me.
[all laugh]
- But still, cheers to that!
- Cheers!
Cheers! Except you.
But, Mother...
what's going to happen to us?
[tense music]
- [server] Mother, this is for you.
- Okay.
Thank you.
[Aleta] Thank you.
[tense music continues]
[Gab] Let me see that.
[Matthew] Excuse me.
[Andrea] Give me that.
Fifty percent to Mother Aleta
50 percent split among you three.
So that means you all own SAM?
Oh, shoot, now I've sobered up.
- Mother? Mother!
- [Aleta] You're welcome!
Oh, oh, oh!
That's a loan! You have to pay me!
Hug me and I'll bill you tomorrow.
I'll just kiss you.
[Noemi] Sofie!
- [Sofie] I still have a manager!
- Mother.
Uh...
Cheers.
- [Camille] Cheers!
- [Gab] To Mother Aleta!
- Cheers, Mother!
Cheers to Shine Artist Management!
Yay!
As early as Monday,
we'll rush the office renovations
so we can set up your new office.
I don't want to work
in your deteriorating office.
I'm done managing talents.
And I'm not holding office at SAM.
I have my own office.
I have my own job.
SAM will be your responsibility.
So, Mother, who will be our boss?
Well, I... I want to head SAM.
I have what it takes, I'm qualified.
I'm qualified too.
Me too.
Well, we all are,
and I have a lot of new ideas.
[Andrea] What ideas?
Okay, what do you think, Mother?
What do I think?
Why the heck are you all working
on a weekend?
[Chin] There you go...
There's a time for all that,
but not tonight.
Not tomorrow night.
Maybe on Monday.
[Aleta] Or the next Monday.
One of these Mondays.
[cell phone pings]
- [Andrea] Wait.
- [Aleta] What's that?
[Frank] I mentioned before
that the list
of those tax evaders
was just a partial one.
I have here with me...
another list of tax evaders.
And again, I urge the DIR
to really go after these tax evaders
for the sake of the Filipino people.
"Punch-Punch Crystals.
Polyver Enterprises.
Pressman Incorporated.
Mr. Retivert Yam.
SStrike Enterprises.
Shine Artist Management.
Titular and Associates."
That's it for now.
- Well...
- [sighs]
All I can say is,
to whoever will head SAM...
good luck.
- Good luck.
- [frustrated sigh]
Mother.
[groans]
I found this in Samuel's office.
SAM IS ALL OF YOU
A lot will happen with SAM.
[Aleta] As early as Monday
you have to deal with Frank Villacin.
And if Roderick is going to join you
you will have to deal
with Paul Amir as well.
ABS-CBN is closed,
what are you going to do about that?
The entire industry of movies,
television, all out of sorts.
The issues are unending,
working conditions, working hours
intellectual property rights,
there's a lot.
Even you.
You have issues
in your personal lives.
Relationships that need
to be repaired.
You have talents that rely on you...
for their livelihood.
What do these all mean?
The world is spinning fast,
really fast!
You all have to go with the flow.
But never forget why SAM is here.
Why you keep fighting for SAM.
[Matthew] You know what I think?
[Andrea] Save that for Monday.
Monday.
Monday, guys, okay?
[Matthew] Monday it is.
[mumbles]
Monday...
[somber music]
[Samuel] I used to tell myself...
"Sam...
You know that love is hard."
[in English]
But when it works, it works.
And it feels good!
[in Filipino] I wish I could still
be here at the end of this story.
So I can finally understand
all the reasons
behind all my struggles.
♪ Oh, swing is what it's called ♪
♪ A mixture of boogie and tango ♪
♪ It's the grooviest dance for me ♪
♪ And for all of you, ho ♪
♪ Swing is now the trend ♪
♪ And it's the dance in every disco ♪
- ♪ So swing
- Swing ♪
♪ You swing me, oh ♪
♪ And to this music ♪
♪ I want you to dip me ♪
- ♪ So swing
- Swing ♪
♪ You swing me ♪
♪ Every tune that's new ♪
♪ Every dance that's for disco ♪
♪ Ah-ha ♪
♪ But I became hooked ♪
♪ On an old dance
That became trendy ♪
♪ This is that dance ♪
♪ Ah, swing is what it's called ♪
♪ A mixture of boogie and tango ♪
♪ It's the grooviest dance for me ♪
♪ And for all of you, ho ♪
♪ Swing is now the trend ♪
♪ And it's the dance in every disco ♪
- ♪ So swing
- Swing ♪
♪ You swing me, oh ♪
♪ And to this music ♪
♪ I want you to dip me ♪
- ♪ So swing
- Swing ♪
♪ You swing me ♪
♪ Ah-ha ♪
- ♪ So swing
- Swing ♪
♪ You swing me ♪
[closing theme music]